Hello friends, my name is Abhishek Goyal
and welcome to my channel Invest E Show.
Friends, in today's market, every health
insurance company is launching a new product every second or third month.
Recently,
Care launched its Ultimate Care product.
Before that, Star
launched Star Superstar. Along with this,
other companies in the market like their
Ratio 2.0 is a very good product. Also,
IIC launched its Elevate plan six months ago. So, in
this way, there are
many companies in the market whose products are trending
and people are somewhere confused about which
product they should buy. So today in this video,
we will compare these four products,
compare their premiums,
cover their USPs and finally
give our own opinion as to which
product you should buy. Let's do the
comparison. Before moving ahead in the video, first you have
come to the channel for the first time, please subscribe it so that
all of you keep getting such better information. Then,
if you like the content, like and
share it. Your every like
motivates us to keep making such informational videos.
Let's do the comparison
friends, first of all let's talk about the
variants here friends, here you
get five variants in n,
you do not get any variant in any other product, if we
talk about sum insured then here
in all the plans you get a minimum sum insured of ₹5 lakh, if we
talk about the maximum limit then here
in Star Superstar and IIC you are
also being given the option of unlimited sum insured,
whereas in the other two plans a limit of ₹1 crore has been given, if we
talk about entries then
in almost all the plans the minimum entries is
91 days, maximum entries limit is
65 years, here in Niva Per Ratio 2.0 the
age limit is
125 years, there is no limit in the other two plans,
if a person is
taking a family parent policy then
in Star Superstar and Ultimate Care
his child can stay only for a maximum of 25 years,
after that he will have to take a separate individual
policy, whereas in the other two plans  A
limit of up to 30 years has been given in the plans.
Talking about room rent, there is
no limit in the first three plans. Whereas,
your ICS Elevate plan
provides a single private AC room. Talking about pre and
post hospital expenses,
here in Star Superstar and ICICI
you get 90 and 180 days free post.
In the remaining two plans, you are being given 60 days. In
case of pre hospital and 180
days are being given. In Niva Per Ratio 2.0
and Ultimate Care, only 90 days are being given.
Talking about cumet bonus, that is,
if there is no claim in your policy tomorrow, then the
company increases your base sum every year.
Here, different limits have been given in every plan.
If you
look here, n is the highest limit where
every year the company increases your base sum by 100%,
which increases up to a maximum of 1000%.
Whereas in ICS  Elevate has the
lowest increment of 20, which
increases to a maximum of 100%.
In all four variants, if you have a claim tomorrow,
it is not reduced.
Talking about the restore benefit, that is,
if tomorrow your base sum is exhausted due to a claim or
your coolant bonus is exhausted, then the
company restores your base
sum.
Here, you are being given unlimited restoration in all four plans.
Restoration is also being given to the same person for the same illness.
However,
in the ICICI Elevate plan, if the same person wants to
use the restoration benefit for the same illness, there should be a
minimum gap of 45 days.
Talking about road ambulance,
you are being given sum-short coverage in all four variants.
Talking about air ambulance,
here in the first two plans you are
given a limit of Rs 5 lakh, whereas in Ultimate and
ICICI you are being given up to sum-short coverage.
In ICICI, you are getting optional
coverage. Here, friends,
wherever we have written 'O' in brackets,
it is being provided as optional; it is
not an inbuilt feature. Next is domus
hospitalization. So, in all the four variants,
you are being given coverage of sum insured.
Coverage of some diseases is
not available under domus hospitalization,
like 15 such diseases are
not covered in Star, 12 diseases are not covered in Ultimate Care,
again 15 diseases are not covered in all other plans.
Day care treatment
means such diseases for which
hospital is not required in today's date, like
kidney stone treatment or
cataract operation. So, all
types of day care procedures are being given in all the plans
and up to date coverage is available. Organ donor
means that if any organ of your body
fails tomorrow and if someone
donates the organ, then all its expenses are covered
up to date in all the four plans.
Free health checkup. So, as soon as you
take the policy, you get free health checkup in all the plans.  It
is on a cashless basis
for which you have to go to their center
and your health checkup is done for free
here, but friends, it is inbuilt in it.
In all other plans, you will
need to pay its premium separately. Next is
modern treatment, so all types of
modern IIDA treatments are covered under sum to
sum coverage in all four plans.
Next is AYUSH treatment, so
Ayurveda, Yoga, Unani Siddha, Homeopathy,
all these types of alternative treatments are
also covered sum to sum in all four plans.
Next is consumer items, so non-
medical items like gloves, masks, PP kit,
which normally cost 5 to 10 rupees of our hospital bills,
so if you
want coverage for all of them as well, then it is an optional benefit
available in all four plans, which you
can add by paying an extra premium.
Next is deductible, so if you
choose deductible in your policy, where
you have to choose a certain percentage or an
amount and whatever
deductible you choose, then whatever
bill comes in the future, that much will be borne by you.  You will have to pay the
rest of the health insurance company, against which the
company
provides a discount of a certain percentage in your premium,
so here you are being
given the option of detachable in three plans, here
you do
not get the option of detachable in Ultimate Care, next is Compassion
Travel, so if tomorrow you are
in a city other than your city and there a life
threatening situation arises due to any
illness or accidental injury, then your
immediate member gets the expenses of coming to you, so
here you get
its cover coverage in Star Superstar and ICICI Elevate plan,
whereas you do
not get its coverage in the other two plans, next is
Premium Freeze Benefit, so this is today's
trending feature where the company does
not change your premium until you do
not have any claim, here
you are being given its benefit in Star Superstar and Rio 2.0,
next is
Premium Pay By, so this is again a unique feature
where if you do not have any claim, then the
company returns your premium after a certain number of years, so
here Ultimate
This feature is available in K, but not in the other three plans.
Next is
Ner Multiplier. This is again a unique feature
where if a person pays the policy premium for 2 or 3
years together, then
whatever is his sum insured for
three years, he can claim it together.
For example, if a person has
taken a sum insured of Rs 10 lakh, then his
sum insured for 3 years becomes Rs 30 lakh. So if a
claim of Rs 30 lakh comes in one go, then the
company pays the entire amount. So,
you get this feature in Ultimate Care, but
this feature is not available in the other three plans.
Next is Wellness Program.
If you are maintaining a healthy life,
which the company will monitor through an app, accordingly the
company provides a discount of a
certain percentage in your renewal premium.
Next is
Maternity Coverage. Here you get
maternity coverage in Star Superstar and IIC.
However, here the company has
given a waiting period of two years and
age.  An optional benefit is given for which
you have to pay an additional premium. Along with this,
friends, the company also provides you estimated
reproduction treatment and
newborn baby coverage
under these two plans. Now let's talk about the
optional coverage which is available in these products.
First of all, let's talk about the
option coverage which is available in Star Superstar. So
here you get limitless
care, where if you put any particular
claim under
limitless care, then the
insured company
gives you the entire money relative to your sum. Annual health
checkup, as I told you, you get free
health checkup on a cashless basis.
Consumer covers, as I told you earlier,
non-medical items like gloves, masks, diapers, guts,
so you also get coverage for 68 non-medical items.
If you take this option of
maternity coverage, then the company is
providing you maternity coverage of ₹1 lakh here.
Quick Shed: If a person has
asthma, BP, sugar, etc. before taking the policy  If you do
n't want any waiting period for a disease like cholesterol, then you can get
all the waiting period reduced within Quick Shed,
up to 30 days. Next is
Superstar Bonus. Here the company gives you 100%
cumet bonus which is an unlimited
type increase. If you wish, you
can include your better half in the policy right now. Where if
you are getting married in the future, then
whoever is your spouse, does
not need to serve any waiting period.
Next is Specified Disease Waiting Period. As usual, the
waiting period in the policy is two years, but you can
reduce it to one year by paying an extra premium.
PD Waiting Period. Here
again, by paying an extra premium, you
can reduce your PD Waiting Period
from 3 years to 1 year. Next is
Smart Network. So, if you choose this option, then the
company provides a discount of 15% on your premium.
But here the
condition of the company is that you have to get the
treatment done in their Smart Network Hospital.  If
you get treatment at a non-smart network hospital,
you have to pay a
copayment of 15%. Along with this, the company is
giving you the option of voluntary copayment and voluntary detachable, where
you are being given a certain percentage option ranging from
10% to 50% and
in voluntary detachable, you are
given a detachable option ranging from 10% to 10%. If
you choose this, your premium gets
reduced by a certain percentage. But
whichever deductible you choose,
you will have to pay whatever claim comes in the future.
Rest of the health insurance company provides
room rate modification. As usual,
you get all categories of rooms in the policy,
but you can get it as a shared
room or a single private EC room in your policy,
due to which the company provides you a discount of certain percentage in the premium.
Next is international second opinion. So, if
a person gets a serious disease
and wants to take an international second opinion, then the
company also provides that service.
Provides durable medical
equipment, so friends, many times it happens that
due to any illness or injury, we get
durable medical equipment
like oxygen concentrator or
wheelchair walker, so the company provides coverage of up to
₹ lakh for all these. Next is
Compassionate Visit, so here the company has
provided coverage of up to ₹ 1000000 under
Compassionate Visit Hospital Cash Benefit, apart from
normal bill. If you choose this option, then the
company gives you a separate cover ranging from ₹ 1000 to
₹ 5000000. The
first option cover
is Deductible, where the company is
giving you the option of deducted from 20000 to 1 lakh. Next is Safeguard
Benefit, so here the company is
giving the option of Safeguard Benefit Plus, if you choose which, then you
get coverage for non-medical items like Gloss Mask PP Kits.  It is
based on the annexure given by the company.
Next is personal accident cover. So if
this person takes the option, then here
if a person dies or becomes
permanently disabled, then according to the
sum insured he
gives him money. Next is
hospital cash benefit. So here the company is providing
hospital cash benefit of Rs. 000 to Rs. 000.
Next is disease
management. So if a person does not want
any waiting period for his pre-existing disease,
then if he chooses this option, then
he starts getting coverage immediately.
Now let's talk about the optional
coverage that you get in Ultimate Care. The
first optional coverage is
Annual Health Checkup. So again, here
all the insured members
get free health checkup on cash back basis. Instant cover. So
here the
person starts getting coverage for all the A BCD diseases after 30 days.
Claim sheet. So for non-
medical items like glasses, masks, pipe kits, etc.
Coverage of all types of 68 non-medical items starts getting available by taking this option.
Next is PD Wait
Period Modification: If a person wants to
use the waiting period of his pre-exit disease, then if he chooses this option, then
he can reduce it to one year or two years.
Infinity Bonus: So again, here the
company is giving 100% renewal bonus every year,
which keeps on increasing unlimitedly.
Next is OPD cover: So here the
company provides you free consultation of
all types of general physician, specialist consultation up to a
certain limit on a cashless basis.
Now let's talk about the optional cover which
you get ICC: So here the first
optional cover is Infit Care: So again, here the
company gives you power where
whatever is your sum insured relative to the sum
insured, whatever is the claim amount, the
company gives it to you completely. Power Booster: So here the
company gives you 100% cumulative bonus every year,
which is unlimited type.  It keeps increasing,
next is jump start, so
if a person has a disease like
asthma, BP, sugar, cholesterol or
obesity before taking the policy, if he chooses this option,
then he starts getting coverage for all those diseases
after 30 days,
claim protector, coverage of non-medical items starts
getting, inflation
protector, apart from normal
curative bonus, this is your power booster,
apart from this, if you choose this, then
here based on inflation the company separately
increases your sum, which is
approximate per
annum, domestic air ambulance, so
here you get coverage of domestic air ambulance as well,
you get the sum insured, next is
dependent accommodation benefit, so here
if the insured child is admitted in the hospital, then
separately the company provides a cash benefit of
₹1 for whoever is with him,
which is
available for a maximum of 10 days, next
is room
modified, your premium increases and
Compassionate visit is decreased, so here you
get a coverage of compassionate travel of ₹2000000 in a year, nursing at home here
₹2000000, here you get newborn baby coverage
which normally
comes under your maternity cost, vaccination of
newborn baby, this also again
comes under your maternity cost,
durable medical equipment cover is also available here, the
company is providing coverage of up to ₹1 lakh,
next is convenience benefit,
so if a person is
admitted in the hospital for more than 10 days, then the company provides him a separate
cash benefit of up to ₹2000000,
next is health checkup, so if you
choose this option, all the insured members
get free health checkup on a
cashless basis, next is befit, so if you
choose this option, then all the
network diagnostic centers of the company, pharmacy
centers or any of their wellness
centers are covered there.  You get a certain
percentage discount if you
avail their services. Next is
teleconsultation. Here
you
can get unlimited consultation from the company's network doctors for small health-
related issues. Next is the option to
reduce the maternity coverage waiting period.
Here, as usual, the waiting
period for maternity coverage in the product is two years.
You can reduce it by 10 years.
Next is voluntary copayment. Here, the
company has given the option of copayment ranging from 10% to 50%.
Next is network
advantage. Here, the company
provides you a premium discount of 10% if
you choose this option. But if
you get a claim tomorrow and get treatment at another network
hospital, then a
computation of 20% is levied there. Next
is personal accident cover. Here, the company is
also providing personal accident coverage of up to ₹1 lakh.
Next is critical
illness cover. Here, the company provides coverage for 20 listed
critical illnesses.  It
is providing with the sum insured of 50 lakhs. So if you
choose this, then if any critical incident
occurs, then whatever sum insured you choose, that
company gives you a sum benefit. Now let's
talk about the waiting period, as
usual there is an initial waiting period of 30 days
for all diseases except for accidental
claim. There is a waiting period of two years for
specified illnesses which take time to form in our body
like kidney stone,
hernia, piles, cataract, there is a
waiting period of 3 years for pre-existing
diseases, such diseases which we have before taking the policy
like BP, sugar, thyroid, so there is a
waiting period of 3 years for all these plans. Next, speedy loading,
so here if a person has
any disease before taking the policy, then does the
company charge a separate premium for him?
Here, there is a separate charge in O and IC, there is a
loading ranging from 10 to 20 rupees,
whereas there is no loading in the other two plans.
PD reduction means that if
someone has a pre-existing disease and does
not have to serve the waiting period or has to
serve it at a minimum, then is there an option to reduce it?
Here, the option to
reduce is being given in all four plans.
Now, let's talk about network hospitals.
Friends, here the company has more than 10,000
network hospitals, so almost all the
big hospitals are included in their network list.
These numbers can fluctuate
because the network hospitals of the company keep
changing. So, the
numbers we have given are approximate numbers.
You can check out your listed hospital in any city by going to the company's website.
Now, let's talk about the premium.
For your reference, we have
calculated a premium of Rs 10 lakh here for two
adults whose age is 33 and 32 and this is the premium without
riders. The
premium is given for Zone One, Zone Two and Zone Three. So, if you
see here, the highest premium without rider is of
your Star Superstar plan, whereas the
lowest premium is of ICC Elevate plan.
Now, let's talk about some information
related to premium.  So whatever
premium you pay here is location based, it is
not treatment based.
Your premium is charged according to the location where you live. If
you go to a higher hospital for treatment, then there is
no copayment.
Next is premium change. So here
friends, in Star Superstar and nPro 2.0, the
constant premium remains the same until your claim
comes. Whereas
in Ultimate Care, it is age wise, as
your age increases, your
premium keeps changing.
In ICICI Elevate Plan, your premium is sleeve wise,
your premium changes in every 5-year band.
Next is premium payment
option. Here the company has given
you the option of one time installment in all the four plans,
where if you want, you
can pay the premium for one year, and if you
want, you can pay the installment premium.
Talking about the premium period, here the
company is giving you the option of one time premium payment from
one year to five years in Star Superstar and Ultimate Care.
Whereas in Niva Par Yo 2.0 and ICICI,
you are given the option of premium payment from one to three years.
Talking about long term
premium discount, here different
companies offer different premium discounts which varies
from 7.5 to 16.
Credit score discount, so if a
person has a very good credit score
then the company separately provides him premium discount.
Online discount, so if
a person is buying a policy online then the
company is separately providing a premium discount of 5%.
Along with this, the company
also provides some other discounts which you can
check it out whichever policy you are
buying. So friends, in this way we talked about all the
features, options, cover, premium waiting period.
Now let's talk about claim rated
information. First of all, let's talk about income ratio.
Friends, how much
premium did the company receive and how much portion of that did the
company pay towards claim, that
tells us the income ratio. So here the ideal
in cured claim ratio should be 70 to 90. So
here if you look at the star and
ICICI's income claim ratio is on the higher
side, whereas Navapa and Care's income claim
ratio is on a lower side. However, if I
talk about claim settlement ratio, that is, how much
amount the company settled out of the total claims received, then if you
look here, the claim settlement ratio of Nipa and Care
appears to be higher compared
with other two companies. So friends, in this
way we covered everything. I hope you
liked the information. Now let's talk about
which product should be taken. Friends, if
I talk about premium, then obviously
here the premium of Asi Elevate
is the lowest compared with other companies. If I
talk about features wise, then here
I like the feature and overall premium of Ultimate Care compared with other
two companies like n or Star Superstar.
Now,
you can choose the plan according to your requirement.
Which plan would you prefer to take here?
Tell us in the comment box. If you have any
query, then again ask us in the comment box.
We will try to answer your questions.
If you like our content then
like, share and subscribe.
Thank you.